<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-05-12T15:35:32-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/</id><title type="html">FORVM</title><subtitle>Forum is a student-run, scholarly magazine that promotes respectful and intellectual dialogue among Villanova students, faculty, and staff.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Spectacle and the Replacement of Reality</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/spring%202017/2017/05/05/Spectacle-Snap.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spectacle and the Replacement of Reality" /><published>2017-05-05T12:14:01-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-05T12:14:01-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/spring%202017/2017/05/05/Spectacle-Snap</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/spring%202017/2017/05/05/Spectacle-Snap.html">&lt;p&gt;On September 24, 2016, Snap, Inc. heralded its rechristening from “Snapchat” and—as if to furnish evidence of its transfigured identity—its invention of Snap Spectacles. Although these jauntily fashionable video-recording glasses seem innocuous, they unearth and exacerbate a host of the problematic promises embedded in the act of photography itself. As Susan Sontag noted 40 years ago in &lt;em&gt;On Photography&lt;/em&gt;, while the photo can be an artistic medium, it can also be a temptation, luring the unwary photographer into a fraught epistemological framework that exchanges—or, rather, claims to exchange—sight for control, experience for evidence, and image for reality. What Sontag notices as the implicit promises of the camera become, in the Snap Spectacles, ad copy and even—it seems—design inspiration. What the camera hints at, the Spectacles hawk. As a result, while Sontag reveals the problematic nature of the Spectacles, the Spectacles themselves boast their ability to alienate their wearers from their experience and even themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before examining the Spectacles, we must revisit Sontag. Through her essay “In Plato’s Cave,” Sontag explicates how the act of taking a photograph can create a fissure between experiential reality and what society takes as real, a fissure that allows the photographer to construct a new reality. The essay begins with an account of how photography has colonized the experience of reality. Sontag claims that “[p]hotographs furnish evidence” because, even though “[t]he picture may distort…there is always a presumption that something exists, or did exist, which is like what’s in the picture.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The verisimilitude of the photographic image testifies to a real-world referent in a way that a drawn or written description cannot. Although Sontag acknowledges the apparent realism of the photograph, she also observes that “photographers are always imposing standards on their subjects,” making photography “as much an interpretation of the world as paintings and drawings are.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Choosing how—and even what—to photograph provides interpretive agency over the photographic image, agency that distinguishes the photographed image from reality itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the camera constructs photographic images, it reconstructs reality. The camera functions culturally as “the device that makes real what one is experiencing,” no matter how drastically the image differs from the original experience.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Photographs of a smiling group of people demonstrate “that fun was had,” regardless of the insincerity of those smiles in the moment the photographs were taken. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;Sontag exemplifies this reconstruction of experience through tourism. Not only does tourist photography “[limit] experience to a search for the photogenic” but it even makes “having an experience…identical with taking a photograph of it.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Paradoxically, the tourist with the most photographs has had the fullest experience, even though that tourist spent the most time taking photographs and the least time experiencing the trip itself. To furnish the most evidence “that fun was had” is to spend the least time having fun—the evidence undoes what it attests to.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This inversion indicates the extent to which photographed images differ from lived experience. The impulse to take and share photographs—especially through social media—indicates the cultural valuing of the photographically documented over the experientially real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Snap, Inc. unveiled itself through an extended panegyric in &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;, it sold its Spectacles as the ideal vehicle for mastering the reconstructed pseudo-reality created through the camera and consumed through social media. While interesting as an explanation of the features of the Spectacles and the history of Snap, Inc., this article is most significant as Snap, Inc.’s first attempt to shape cultural perceptions of its product. The article profiles the company’s CEO Evan Spiegel, who captures the promise of the Spectacles with bald succinctness and openness—what Sontag revealed through critique, Spiegel celebrates as enticement. He claims that the Spectacles’ recordings allowed him to “see [his] own memory, through [his] own eyes.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:7&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only does Spiegel insist that the Spectacles capture memory, but even that they do so in an unparalleled way—he calls the effect “unbelievable.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Spiegel goes further, claiming that the Spectacles gave him “an experience of the experience” that was “the closest [he had] ever come to feeling like [he] was there again.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:9&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The images from the Spectacles, he claims, provide access both to the truest vision of the experience and to a newer, superior version of that—the “experience of the experience.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:10&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:10&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; His testimony about his use of the Spectacles explicitly promises what, according to Sontag, the camera itself offer implicitly. The Spectacles suggest access to and power over a purer, truer experience of reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the design of the Spectacles optimizes the camera’s innate abilities to usurp the real. The Spectacles elide the camera and eyesight, suggesting that the camera perfectly captures experiential reality. Not only are the cameras next to the lenses, but they even take rounded images ostensibly closer to human eyesight.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:11&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:11&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The cameras subtly claim to replace our eyes; the automatic uploading of video onto the user’s “Snap Memory” frankly promises to replace our memory.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:12&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:12&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; By claiming to become human perception and memory, the Spectacles assert the veracity of their videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notably, though, the design serves to heighten the illusion, but not to transform it into reality. The rounded images serve both to suggest the proximity to eyesight and to make those images more presentable and malleable: they fit more easily into either portrait or landscape aspect ratios.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:13&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:13&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Similarly, if the wearer of the Spectacles glances to the side without tilting his or her head, the recording will not match that wearer’s view. Likewise, unless the Spectacles record a shade darker than other cameras, the image will differ from the wearer’s sight through the sunglasses’ tinted lenses. The design of the Spectacles indicates not that its engineers sought to rigorously undo the division between the camera and its user’s sight, but rather that those engineers sought to create a product that resoundingly purports to do so. What matters is not fulfilling but indulging the fantasy of the camera that captures experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This fantasy, however, is no safer than the temptations that once led Marlowe’s theologically-naïve doctor to damnation. As Sontag recognizes, photography alienates at the same time it authorizes—it replaces a real embeddedness within the world with an illusory domination of it. Sontag connects the creation of photography to modernity’s “surplus of Faustian energy,” energy that craves something “that feels like knowledge—and, therefore, power.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:14&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:14&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Her allusion to Faust and her qualification that photography “feels like”—rather than “is”—knowledge and power signifies both the seductiveness and the unreality of the relationship to the world that photography creates.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:15&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:15&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spectacles situate their wearers in a series of paradoxes that demonstrate how photography alienates and reconstructs the photographer just as much as it does the world. One of the most interesting consequences of the Spectacles’ design is their inability to take the most ubiquitous of modern photographs: the selfie. Yet, even though they cannot take a selfie—the alleged hallmark of modern self-absorption—the Spectacles have little to do with modesty. Promotional images of the Spectacles feature models posing—nude, at least given the implications of the bare shoulders and suggestively cropped image—with the glasses.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:16&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:16&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;16&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Bold colors, coy expressions, and, for female models, brightly-painted nails mark the Spectacles as haute couture fashion rather than obtrusive technology. The chic frames offset the visible cameras, marking their difference both from ordinary sunglasses and from the notoriously gauche Google Glass. The Spectacles situate their wearers at a paradoxical point between invisibility and distinctiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the name of the product constructs the wearers’ contradictory position. The word “spectacles” refers both to glasses—the apparent derivation of the name—and, more subtly, to events that draw peoples’ attention. More than an innocent pun, the name of the Spectacles announces the wearers’ dual sightedness and visibility. The Spectacles, and by implication the camera itself, promise not only to enable vision, memory, and experience, but also to testify to the photographer’s meaningful existence. This testimony, though, effaces that existence at the same time it superficially validates it. The photographer exists as the producer of photographs, meaning he or she exists in service of the camera. The camera becomes the end and its user the means—the life provides the photographs. The Spectacles boast this relationship; they, not their wearers, are the spectacles. The inability to take a selfie indicates not a resurgence of modesty but an erasure of identity. Sontag eloquently demonstrates how photography can drain real experience of its significance. Using her essay as a frame with which to analyze the Snap Spectacles reveals a corollary of what she describes: when real experiences lose their significance, so do the people who experience them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Susan Sontag, “In Plato’s Cave,” in On Photography (New York: Picador. 1977), 5.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Ibid, 6-7.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Ibid, 9.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Ibid.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Ibid, 9, 23.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Ibid, 9.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:7&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Evan Spiegel, qtd. in Seth Stevenson, “Snapchat Releases First Product, Spectacles,” The Wall Street Journal. (24 Sept. 2016.) Web.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:8&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Ibid.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:9&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Ibid.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:9&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:10&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Ibid.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:10&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:11&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Stevenson, “Snapchat Releases First Product, Spectacles.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:11&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:12&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Spectacles,” Spectacles. (Snap, Inc.) Web.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:12&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:13&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Stevenson, “Snapchat Releases First Product, Spectacles.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:13&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:14&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Sontag, “In Plato’s Cave,” 4.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:14&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:15&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Ibid.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:15&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:16&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Specatcles.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:16&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Stephen Purcell</name></author><category term="Spring 2017" /><summary type="html">On September 24, 2016, Snap, Inc. heralded its rechristening from “Snapchat” and—as if to furnish evidence of its transfigured identity—its invention of Snap Spectacles. Although these jauntily fashionable video-recording glasses seem innocuous, they unearth and exacerbate a host of the problematic promises embedded in the act of photography itself. As Susan Sontag noted 40 years ago in On Photography, while the photo can be an artistic medium, it can also be a temptation, luring the unwary photographer into a fraught epistemological framework that exchanges—or, rather, claims to exchange—sight for control, experience for evidence, and image for reality. What Sontag notices as the implicit promises of the camera become, in the Snap Spectacles, ad copy and even—it seems—design inspiration. What the camera hints at, the Spectacles hawk. As a result, while Sontag reveals the problematic nature of the Spectacles, the Spectacles themselves boast their ability to alienate their wearers from their experience and even themselves.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Utility of Open Dialogue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/spring%202017/2017/05/05/Open-Dialogue.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Utility of Open Dialogue" /><published>2017-05-05T12:14:01-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-05T12:14:01-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/spring%202017/2017/05/05/Open-Dialogue</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/spring%202017/2017/05/05/Open-Dialogue.html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, our nation has revisited the question of what type of speech should be given a platform. The Charles Murray lecture, as well as the disinvitation of two queer activists, has ignited the question of free speech on our campus. As a Villanovan, I’ve felt the same call as my peers to reflect on this issue. I am an engineering student and a political centrist; I’m not the type to obsess over the trivialities of politics. Yet, the debate on allowable speech feels like it’s too important to ignore. I’ve found the response from both students and faculty to be concerning as it points to the larger problem of an unsuccessful (if not totally absent) dialogue between ideologically opposed groups. The political discourse on our campus is insular, but it has the potential to bridge differences, forge understanding, and build a stronger Villanova community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having attended the Charles Murray lecture, I witnessed the full spectrum of Villanova community members.  The talk appeared as though it would begin undisturbed, but what started as a loud purposeful cough grew into protesters disrupting the lecture by covering Murray’s podium with a sign and overriding his voice.  The tension and discomfort was real.  Once the lecture progressed it became evident that the lecture was unrelated to the protests that they spawned.  To those uninterested in classical liberalism in the Trump era, the speech may even be described as mundane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of this event and the evident fracturing of community on our campus, we can all agree that a more harmonious Villanova community is an ideal worth striving for. Harmony is not characterized by the dominance of a single perspective. Rather, harmony is the result of allowing differing perspectives to be heard. It is the result of caring about each unique and necessary voice. Unfortunately, the current mood on campus is what is often called “Villanova nice”: a pervasive political apathy and patronizing politeness. This attitude among students is not problematic because students do not care about issues of justice – it is problematic because people have opinions but choose to conceal them. Concealing the truth out of politeness is a disservice that hinders intellectual and moral development. Distasteful thoughts lay dormant and unchallenged. It is important that everyone be allowed to speak, no matter how horrendous their beliefs. This is necessary for challenging the unsavory thoughts that lay in the minds of people who are too agreeable to speak up. The importance of controversial speakers becomes evident because it normalizes sharing how we think. How can we challenge each other to dismantle preconceived notions if no one dares to speak out about them? Tolerating the intolerable allows the intolerable concepts to be reshaped and reformed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the truth exists—as the existence of acceptable and unacceptable tenets would suggest—then the utility of free speech is a means for striving ever closer to determining what it is. Censorship in any form, whether of Murray or the uninvited queer speakers, is terrifying because it hinders our ability to discover the truth; without open debate we are prone to falling into our own unchecked ideologies. The current hyperpolarization between the nation’s two primary political parties serves as a dangerous example of unchecked ideological drifting. The political right does not care about what the political left thinks of its ideas, while the left no longer cares about what the right thinks of its ideas.  Neither side seeks discourse with the opposing party because the language that each group uses has become so divergent. We lack a common language to speak with someone with diametrically opposing viewpoints from our own. This undermines the persuasiveness of both sides of the political spectrum. Any discussion is likely to become a rhetorical dance around an issue rather than mutual understanding of the other’s perspective. Censorship, whether enforced or self-enforced, allows this divergence to occur and grow wider over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we stop defending the rationale behind supposedly obvious ideas, they become vulnerable to previously disproven ideas. We can see this phenomenon happening now. The right is confronting resurgent nationalism from the alt-right while the left is confronting resurgent illiberal Marxist theory. Stigma of various methods of thought is used to combat these long dead ideologies instead of reason and logic. Censorship (through social stigma or through the banning of contentious speakers) of distasteful perspectives is the direct cause of the death of logic in cross-ideological debate. Furthermore, advocating for censorship of any form justifies your own censorship. The calls to silence Murray can equally be waged against those who call for the silencing.  We should not be afraid of any ideology or pattern of thought because if our ideas can be so easily demolished by freedom of speech, then it is far more likely the ideas were never true or cohesive to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some students and faculty on our campus have argued that certain ideas should not be given a platform at a private university. They were not arguing against the constitutional right to free speech per se, so much as they were arguing about who is qualified to speak on our campus. Shouldn’t a book like &lt;em&gt;The Bell Curve&lt;/em&gt; immediately bar the author from any sort of serious platform? Those of us who support open debate would answer that a platform is not an endorsement—it’s an arena. The competing perspectives have the opportunity to argue why the controversial speaker is wrong and to provide the rational arguments for their own beliefs. Only ideologies that lack any sort of internal logic or foundational truth need to rely on censorship to preserve their persuasiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the heart of a liberal arts education lies the belief that the truth exists, can be known, and is worth seeking. Without strict pursuit of and adherence to the truth about reality, we lack the intellectual foundation on which to strive for the good life. Freedom of speech is often about determining the truth of political issues and social justice, but it has a higher purpose. We need to challenge each other on our conception of reality and our place in it. Open dialogue on the most fundamental questions of human existence is essential for the individual to properly order the good in his or her life. Moreover, freedom of speech allows us to openly explore questions on the nature of the ideal community. If we wish to knit Villanova community together with something stronger than the feigned “Villanova niceness” we have presently, we need not look further than this fundamental premise: censorship of any form has no place here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Derek Fake &amp; Gina Arnold</name></author><category term="Spring 2017" /><summary type="html">Over the past few years, our nation has revisited the question of what type of speech should be given a platform. The Charles Murray lecture, as well as the disinvitation of two queer activists, has ignited the question of free speech on our campus. As a Villanovan, I’ve felt the same call as my peers to reflect on this issue. I am an engineering student and a political centrist; I’m not the type to obsess over the trivialities of politics. Yet, the debate on allowable speech feels like it’s too important to ignore. I’ve found the response from both students and faculty to be concerning as it points to the larger problem of an unsuccessful (if not totally absent) dialogue between ideologically opposed groups. The political discourse on our campus is insular, but it has the potential to bridge differences, forge understanding, and build a stronger Villanova community.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">No title</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/spring%202017/2017/05/05/No-Title.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No title" /><published>2017-05-05T12:14:01-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-05T12:14:01-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/spring%202017/2017/05/05/No-Title</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/spring%202017/2017/05/05/No-Title.html">&lt;p&gt;Why does racism exist?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is it someone can make a judgment about me by how I look&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but not who I am?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is it that I appear more frightening than the average bear?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean one glance and you can’t see if I have a criminal record or if I’ve been suspended from school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the problem isn’t my character: it’s my black skin, my big lips and my nappy hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it wasn’t seen as beautiful to your ancestors and that mindset has been passed down from your plantation owning, black women raping, black home wrecking, white hood wearing great great great granddaddy, almost as much as my bronze skin was inherited from ancient kings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These chains on our thoughts and perceptions keep us all chained down, though we have wings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why do we cling?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do we assume we know a person well enough to fear them based on a picture or a glance?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because we refuse to see with our eyes as God gave them to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see through a lens over our minds that makes us perceive people who look different than us as nightmarish!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s because when we look we don’t use our eyes. If we did we’d see people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we look with our minds and our memories. We see a person and remember that story of the gang banger or thief on TV, and how
he looked like me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as opposed to seeing a person with eyes, legs, arms, ears, and a heart and saying, “Wow. He looks just like me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is I have to do something extra to prove my humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a white man who writes a poem and is a poet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a black man who writes poem is a gangster rapper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A black man who kills is a gang member or thug&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a white man who belongs to the gang run by Uncle Sam and attacks all that is not Red White and Blue, is just mentally ill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A black man in poverty is there because he chose to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A white man is just down on his luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blame your ancestors for why this mindset was created, but look no further than the mirror as to why it still exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look no further than a selfie for why hatred still persists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You question why your white son has no black friends when his perception of who is worthy of his friendship was influenced by you
clutching your handbag tightly when a young black kid his age walked past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not saying don’t take precaution,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m saying don’t have irrational fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not saying don’t be afraid,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m saying don’t paint my whole race with your broad brush,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then call me a racist when I get pissed at white mothers looking at me like i don’t belong in my own neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because in reality, the only difference between your perception of a neighborhood and ‘the hood’ is the color of the people
living in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why does racism still exist?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because you allow it to, and because you breed it into your children.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Clifton Porter</name></author><category term="Spring 2017" /><summary type="html">Why does racism exist?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Highway Billboards Burn School District Leaders</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/spring%202017/2017/05/05/Highway-Billboards.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Highway Billboards Burn School District Leaders" /><published>2017-05-05T12:14:01-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-05T12:14:01-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/spring%202017/2017/05/05/Highway-Billboards</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/spring%202017/2017/05/05/Highway-Billboards.html">&lt;p&gt;Propaganda.  From the early wars to the most recent American Presidential election, propaganda has influenced and motivated a diverse audience in both a positive and negative light.  While some advertisements castigate people, companies, and organizations, others highlight successes and achievements.  Billboards on highways are argued to be the most entertaining form of propaganda on the market today, seeing as they captivate drivers and their passengers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highway billboards around the city of Philadelphia are a public outcry regarding the injustice throughout the city, particularly on the subject of income inequality.  The purpose of these billboards ranges from brand marketing to company profiles.  But a recent billboard in Center City Philadelphia is one of the first advertisements that directly addresses public figures and the need for more investment in education—a topic that is heavily argued upon in the United States today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A public high school teacher has erected a billboard on the I-95 Interstate funded primarily by donations that calls out Philadelphia Mayor Kenney, the city’s School Reform Commission, and Superintendent William Hite.  In the February, George Bezanis, a teacher at Central High School, raised over $5000 in just five days on the gofundme.com page with the hope that these city and school district leaders will give Philadelphia teachers a contract.  Countless members of the Philadelphia Federation of Teachers have not received a raise nor a proper contract in 5 years while working in the School District of Philadelphia.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bezanis, along with other public school supporters, has now taken action and organized a billboard advertisement that says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Welcome to Philadelphia, where we don’t value our public school children,
5+ years without a raise for our teachers.
With Love, the SRC, Mayor Kenney, Superintendent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The billboard has appeared on the Interstate 95, southbound on the right, at a prime location between the Girard and Central Philadelphia exits.  It was originally planned to be up for four weeks, but as donations continue to pour in, Bezanis and the Philadelphia Federation of Teachers decided to keep it for as long as they can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Philly native, I have witnessed the countless struggles students face while in the District: the high turnover rate of teachers, the lack of learning resources for the students, and the dangerous location of schools.  However, most public officials and state leaders are more concerned with the larger national issues instead of students’ knowledge or improvement in the classroom.  Just recently, the Senate Education Committee in Harrisburg advanced a bill that permits teachers in Pennsylvania to carry a concealed weapon.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  From my experience as an intern reporter for a nonprofit that covers topics in education, efforts should be more dedicated towards local issues, such as a more accurate budget that focuses on providing a better salary for District teachers, instead of issues that involve teachers “packing heat.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This type of public shaming towards public officials and state leaders is still ongoing, despite cries of outrage and embarrassment from the district.  The billboard is still up and many people have now opened their eyes to the serious problems within Philadelphia public schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the years, the city has consequently lost an incredible amount of great educators who left the city to work with better pay in surrounding districts.  What’s more, the newly-appointed Secretary of Education Betsy DeVos strongly advocates school choice and does not believe in public school education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now, how will the children of urban cities, including Philadelphia, receive a proper education to advance and improve their futures, if school districts are unable to pay their teachers and offer support programs?  If these children are the future leaders who will be governing us and making important decisions about our lives, then why aren’t we investing more time into educating and helping them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Sign of the Times.” The Philadelphia Public School Notebook. 2017. &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenotebook.org/articles/2017/02/13/sign-of-the-times&quot;&gt;http://thenotebook.org/articles/2017/02/13/sign-of-the-times&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Pennsylvania bill would allow teachers to pack heat.” The Philadelphia Public School Notebook. 2017 &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenotebook.org/articles/2017/04/20/pennsylvania-bill-would-allow-teachers-to-pack-heat&quot;&gt;http://thenotebook.org/articles/2017/04/20/pennsylvania-bill-would-allow-teachers-to-pack-heat&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Camille De Ramos</name></author><category term="Spring 2017" /><summary type="html">Propaganda. From the early wars to the most recent American Presidential election, propaganda has influenced and motivated a diverse audience in both a positive and negative light. While some advertisements castigate people, companies, and organizations, others highlight successes and achievements. Billboards on highways are argued to be the most entertaining form of propaganda on the market today, seeing as they captivate drivers and their passengers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The False Pretenses of Meritocracy: When Skill Ultimately Comes Down to Money</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/spring%202017/2017/05/05/False-Meritocracy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The False Pretenses of Meritocracy: When Skill Ultimately Comes Down to Money" /><published>2017-05-05T12:14:01-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-05T12:14:01-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/spring%202017/2017/05/05/False-Meritocracy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/spring%202017/2017/05/05/False-Meritocracy.html">&lt;p&gt;In 1958, Michael Young warned the British public about the dangers of a meritocratic society through his work, &lt;em&gt;The Rise of the Meritocracy&lt;/em&gt;. The widely incorrect contemporary spin of his efforts, however, comes as a disappointment.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; When translated into current society’s overarching belief that ability and effort will always equal success for all people, a society controlled by “specialists” seems like a logical resolution to ending global crises such as poverty or global warming. Its principles, however, are inherently problematic, as it leverages the achievements of economically and educationally privileged individuals, purely based on “good expected results.” As a post-modern style of Social Darwinism, social inequality is subsequently distorted and euphemized as meritocratic. By stripping the identity of an individual, meritocracy fools people into thinking that everyone is being treated equally on the same playing field because only the &lt;em&gt;skills&lt;/em&gt; of an individual are highlighted and praised, without regard for gender, race, class, and so forth. Meritocracy as a utopian ideal, however, perpetuates a sense of entitlement and an embrace of elitist tendencies, further marginalizing the common people and the poor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meritocracy becomes a vessel for enforcing a system of social hierarchy that values not money but the education provided by opportunities that are funded by money. Historically, high positions of power are usually given to wealthy white males, implying that the rich and educated only deserve the authority to dictate the laws of society.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This small group of elites is responsible for representing the greater population of ordinary working-class families. After all, even the presidents of the United States primarily consist of rich, Ivy League-educated white males (excluding President Obama who is only half white). This speaks to what Rick Perlstein describes as “who get[s] to be called ‘smart’ and who get[s] called ‘dumb’ [which] is not precisely arbitrary. It is, however, frequently ideological, mediated by institutions (like Yale, or Virginia’s State Colony for Epileptics and Feeble-minded) &lt;em&gt;shot through&lt;/em&gt; with ideology.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; With the amalgamation of complex social experiences, it is virtually impossible to separate a true form of intelligence from perceived intelligence. Smart, thus, becomes more than a characteristic: “‘smart’ is an identity. ‘Smart’ has a politics… a road to authenticity… [that] carries within it its own logic of domination, resistance, resentment.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Intelligence is subsequently seen as a virtue, wherein being “smart” is equated with being “good.” To play the system, people are told to “get smart” and put faith into the socialization of education. Unfortunately for the have-nots, these elitist propensities further elevate the rich, while abandoning the common people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is simple: not everyone has the same opportunities to achieve and cultivate a “skill.” Martin Luther King, Jr. (MLK) highlights this central issue in his work “The Purpose of Education,” where he describes the predominant misconceptions that encompass meritocracy— education, opportunity, and achievement. Instead of thinking of education as a means to an end, “most college men…think that education should equip them with the proper instruments of exploitation so that they can forever trample over the masses,” merely furnishing them with seemingly noble intentions.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; He expresses disappointment in that educated people are influenced by the biases and subjectivity found in propaganda and the news, even though education’s job “must enable one to sift and weigh evidence, to discern the true from the false, the real from the unreal, and the facts from the fiction.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It is problematic that efficiency has become its primary concern. In a speech he delivered at the United Federation of Teachers, MLK questions the wealthy, as they have “never allocated enough resources to build sufficient schools, to compensate adequately its teachers, and to surround [the public] with the prestige our work justifies…[they] pauperize education.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:7&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; These issues impact more than a specific race or socioeconomic class because beyond the demographics of the poor, people have been convinced that education is solely for the purpose of success and deserved only by the successful. This ignorance perpetuates the problem of educational inequality in that those who are educated are entitled to make society’s decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To reject the belief that “opportunity equals success,” therefore, threatens the glorified American Dream scenario. People are told, “America is the great land of opportunity—anyone can succeed!” They are invested in the fabricated proposition that “poverty is a consequence of multiple evils: lack of education restricting job opportunities; poor housing which stultified home life and suppressed initiative; fragile family relationships which distorted personality development.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The quick fix would be to solve these secondary issues and hope that the resolutions would trickle down to eradicate poverty. Unless the United States has a complete upheaval of the current social, political, and educational system, it is doubtful that the American Dream can become a reality. This is a multifaceted issue that calls for a complete transformation of home environments, school systems, property values, and so forth, that have been in place for hundreds of years. Merely offering opportunity for good education or nice housing has proven to be insufficient. Upward mobility, as a result, is impossible for those in cycles of poverty and those who identify as minorities because there is no way to obtain the merit necessary to participate in society. Meritocracy is blind to these underlying social systems, creating a greater divide between the rich and the poor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The promise of meritocratic ideals leads to a false pretense that specific demographic groups have a chance at success. For example, Emilio J. Castilla, a professor at MIT’s Sloan School of Management, examined “how meritocratic ideals and HR practices like pay-for-performance play out in organizations” and uncovered some unexpected inconsistencies.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:9&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Program initiatives claim to provide under-represented groups with equal opportunities, claiming that people are evaluated solely “based on their skills, abilities, and merit, without consideration of their gender, race, sexuality.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:10&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:10&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The claim, however, hides a fallacy that “managers are objective in their assessments [so] there is no need for diversity policies.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:11&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:11&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Castilla’s analysis revealed that non-whites, women, and foreign workers with the same occupations as white men (with same supervisors, human capital, and performance score) receive smaller increases in wages, despite the meritocratic idea that performance determines salary. In collaboration with Indiana University sociology professor Stephen Bernard, Castilla conducted experiments to determine the relationship between company meritocratic values, monetary compensation, and the identity of an employee. When a company stressed their meritocratic ideals, female employees who performed as well as their male counterparts received a smaller salary. The researchers referred to this as “the paradox of meritocracy,” and reveals the antithetical results of meritocratic ideals, as performed by American society.
Proponents of meritocracy claim that financial status can be ignored because skills become the primary source of credit. These same skills, however, are granted on the foundation that wealth has the clout to purchase these particular talents. For example, skills that require many hours of practice and lessons, such as the violin or tennis, must be funded by a big sum of money to pay for top instructors and high quality equipment. There is a limit to having an innate talent for learned skills, such as predicting the market economy or creating laws for an orderly society, and this advantage is limited to a few. For individuals to continue to cultivate these abilities, they must have the financial capacity to continue their education for an extended period of time. Further, sense of entitlement is attached to the development and mastery of particular sets of talents. One could argue that society can provide equal opportunities for everyone, but this would require only a complete restructuring of civilization. As a result, the disregard for money is not a realistic enforcement of meritocracy, and if it is assumed that putting everyone on an equal playing field will solve all social inequality, this is an overstatement.
As Marx proclaims in his essay, the “Power of Money,” people must be valued for who they are and not how they contribute to society. It is so easy to use meritocracy as a mask to disguise the exclusivity of a higher socioeconomic status, denying that money has any leverage in education and merit. Intelligence cannot be an identity, as there are so many social factors that contribute to the unequal availability of education to some and not others. In order to truly respect the dignity of an individual, it is crucial to acknowledge that equality lies in accepting the intrinsic identities and unique perspectives that people can contribute. Skills cultivated through education are merely a vessel for social division.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Michael Young, “Down with meritocracy,” &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt;, June 28, 2001, accessed March 19, 2017, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2001/jun/29/comment&quot;&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2001/jun/29/comment&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Jasmine C. Lee, “Trump’s Cabinet So Far Is More White and Male Than Any First Cabinet Since Reagan’s,” &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;, March 10, 2017, accessed March 19, 2017, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2017/01/13/us/politics/trump-cabinet-women-minorities.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2017/01/13/us/politics/trump-cabinet-women-minorities.html?_r=0&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Rick Perlstein, “Outsmarted,” &lt;em&gt;The Baffler&lt;/em&gt;, Spring 2017, accessed March 19, 2017, &lt;a href=&quot;https://thebaffler.com/salvos/outsmarted-perlstein&quot;&gt;https://thebaffler.com/salvos/outsmarted-perlstein&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Ibid.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt; Valerie Strauss, “Martin Luther King: The problem with ‘so-called educated people’,” &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;, January 17, 2017, accessed March 19, 2017, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/answer-sheet/wp/2015/01/19/martin-luther-kings-prophetic-comments-about-education-reform/?utm_term=.b11666a9b4b7&quot;&gt;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/answer-sheet/wp/2015/01/19/martin-luther-kings-prophetic-comments-about-education-reform/?utm_term=.b11666a9b4b7&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Ibid.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:7&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Ibid.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:8&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Ibid.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:9&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Marianne Cooper, “The False Promise of Meritocracy,” &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;, December 1, 2015, accessed March 19, 2017, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2015/12/meritocracy/418074/&quot;&gt;https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2015/12/meritocracy/418074/&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:9&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:10&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Ibid.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:10&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:11&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Ibid.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:11&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Ana Song</name></author><category term="Spring 2017" /><summary type="html">In 1958, Michael Young warned the British public about the dangers of a meritocratic society through his work, The Rise of the Meritocracy. The widely incorrect contemporary spin of his efforts, however, comes as a disappointment.1 When translated into current society’s overarching belief that ability and effort will always equal success for all people, a society controlled by “specialists” seems like a logical resolution to ending global crises such as poverty or global warming. Its principles, however, are inherently problematic, as it leverages the achievements of economically and educationally privileged individuals, purely based on “good expected results.” As a post-modern style of Social Darwinism, social inequality is subsequently distorted and euphemized as meritocratic. By stripping the identity of an individual, meritocracy fools people into thinking that everyone is being treated equally on the same playing field because only the skills of an individual are highlighted and praised, without regard for gender, race, class, and so forth. Meritocracy as a utopian ideal, however, perpetuates a sense of entitlement and an embrace of elitist tendencies, further marginalizing the common people and the poor. Michael Young, “Down with meritocracy,” The Guardian, June 28, 2001, accessed March 19, 2017, https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2001/jun/29/comment.&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8617;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Anomie in the Second Grade?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/spring%202017/2017/05/05/Anomie.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Anomie in the Second Grade?" /><published>2017-05-05T12:14:01-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-05T12:14:01-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/spring%202017/2017/05/05/Anomie</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/spring%202017/2017/05/05/Anomie.html">&lt;p&gt;Each Wednesday morning last semester I volunteered at Alexander K. McClure School in North Philadelphia.  The school is for children grades Pre-K to fifth grade living in the Hunting Park neighborhood.  On my first day I was assigned as a teacher’s aid to a bilingual second grade classroom.  I had no idea what to expect from this experience, and naturally, I was nervous the first time I walked into the classroom. To my relief, the teacher and all of the students gave me an extremely warm greeting. The students were all so sweet and eager to get to know me, and I was surprised that they addressed me as ‘Miss Kristen’ without even being told.  At the beginning of each day the teacher, Ms. Ramos, would provide me with her lesson plan for that morning.  The typical day consisted of English spelling, grammar, and reading.  I would assist kids that were struggling, read to them, and answer any question that they had to the best of my ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On McClure’s website it is stated that their mission is to instill a love of learning in the students and to close the achievement gap by preparing students for college.  This sentiment is most likely common among all schools because they are institutions of growth and learning—or at least they should be.  One huge challenge that McClure faces in pursuit of their goal is the language barrier.  Many of the children in the classrooms speak both English and Spanish fluently, but the children are still at varying levels in both.  Spanish is a handful of the children’s first language and they speak little, if any, English at home.  These students tend to fall behind in class when they are completing exercises or worksheets in English and often become discouraged. This leads them to simply refuse to do their work.  What makes this even more troubling is that the teacher usually does not slow down for these students or work extra hours with them because she has a lesson plan to get through.  This is a crucial period in these children’s lives for language development. If they fall behind now, it will be much more difficult for them to catch up, if they are able to at all.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another barrier is the qualification and training of the teachers.  The woman that I have been working with is extremely sweet and well-intentioned, but she is quite young and I wonder if she is actually equipped to teach in this setting.  She is fluent in Spanish, which is helpful when it comes to communicating effectively with students and teaching lessons in Spanish.  However, on occasion she will turn to me for the pronunciation or meaning of an English word.  The lesson plans also seem to be relatively generic and unstructured.  She will typically pass out a phonics worksheet and have the students complete it with little to no direction.  This is not beneficial at all for the students since they often are unsure of what to do and don’t get feedback. They will never be able to learn from their mistakes.  Additionally, the teacher will sometimes split the class into two groups to complete the worksheets and often put me in charge of the students who have the most trouble or are the least advanced.  I do my best with them but they would certainly be better off with someone who has more teaching experience than I do.  The teacher tends to switch quickly and randomly from one activity to another without much explanation.  This confuses the students and makes it hard for them to follow along, leaving them more behind than they were before.  While it is unrealistic to always make sure that every student is on the same page when there is only one teacher responsible for over twenty students, I believe a little more effort could, and should, be made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is challenging to look at a classroom full of innocent second graders from a criminological standpoint, but this institution’s practices seem to be consistent with social science research on delinquency.  According to Durkheim’s anomie theory, the disadvantaged are motivated to commit crime and the motivation stems from a poor balance between social structure and cultural definitions of success.  In this case, McClure’s mission for preparing students for college is the “success” in question and the social structure is to what degree the school actually achieves this.  If the students are not getting an education to the same caliber of their higher socioeconomic counterparts, they will be put at a greater disadvantage in the future.  This could lead to the individual adaptation of accepting the goal of attending college yet not having access to a proper education to achieve this goal.  It could also lead to retreatism or rebellion if the children go on to reject the societal goals.
 
One method to measure whether or not the school is providing the students with sufficient means to achieve their goal is to look at standardized state testing scores.  Results from the Pennsylvania System of State Assessments (PSSA) in 2015-2016 show that only twenty percent of McClure’s third graders were proficient in English and eleven percent were efficient in mathematics.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  These percentages only decline as the grade level increases.  The school that these students will go on to attend, Clemente Roberto Middle School, shows much less promising numbers with only six percent of eighth graders proficient in English and two percent performing at their grade level in math.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  This will leave students extremely behind once they reach high school.  In fact, the Olney Charter High School that they will attend has a dropout rate of almost fifty percent.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  This will inevitably minimize their chances of attending college, thus limiting their legitimate economic opportunity.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the low standardized test scores, the Hunting Park neighborhood shows opposite patterns for poverty and crime rates.  According to data published in The Philadelphia Inquirer, forty percent of Hunting Park residents are living in poverty.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  The average household income in 2015 was just over $22,000.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  This would most likely pose as a major barrier to children’s academic achievement.  Parents would be less likely to have the resources to afford a tutor for their children if they are falling behind in class.  If the child is not helped early on they will not have a strong platform to build off of while they progress through school.  If they do beat the odds and eventually graduate from high school, it would be difficult to afford the inflating college tuitions.  Unfortunately, many colleges and universities have tuitions far above the annual household income of children coming out of this area.  Even if the child can get into these schools, the financial burden may be too great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I absolutely gained a great deal from this opportunity.  I now have a deeper and first hand understanding of the educational system and how it relates to delinquency.  I also formed many positive bonds with the students and was not only able to assist them in their learning process, but I also learned more than I ever thought would be possible from such young children.  It is extremely valuable to experience environments that differ from one’s own in order to develop a more informed worldview.  I was challenged each day to be more compassionate, patient, and open minded through my interactions.  I only wish there could be more structured and focused teaching in order to give these children the best possible chance at success.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greatschools.org/pennsylvania/philadelphia/2149-Mcclure-Alexander-K-School&quot;&gt;http://www.greatschools.org/pennsylvania/philadelphia/2149-Mcclure-Alexander-K-School&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greatschools.org/pennsylvania/philadelphia/2161-Clemente-Roberto-Middle-School&quot;&gt;http://www.greatschools.org/pennsylvania/philadelphia/2161-Clemente-Roberto-Middle-School&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greatschools.org/pennsylvania/philadelphia/11415-Olney-Charter-High-School/quality&quot;&gt;http://www.greatschools.org/pennsylvania/philadelphia/11415-Olney-Charter-High-School/quality&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;See The Philadelphia Inquirer, &lt;a href=&quot;http://data.inquirer.com/crime/neighborhood/hunting-park&quot;&gt;http://data.inquirer.com/crime/neighborhood/hunting-park&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.city-data.com/neighborhood/Hunting-Park-Philadelphia-PA.html&quot;&gt;http://www.city-data.com/neighborhood/Hunting-Park-Philadelphia-PA.html&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Kristen Ryan</name></author><category term="Spring 2017" /><summary type="html">Each Wednesday morning last semester I volunteered at Alexander K. McClure School in North Philadelphia.  The school is for children grades Pre-K to fifth grade living in the Hunting Park neighborhood.  On my first day I was assigned as a teacher’s aid to a bilingual second grade classroom.  I had no idea what to expect from this experience, and naturally, I was nervous the first time I walked into the classroom. To my relief, the teacher and all of the students gave me an extremely warm greeting. The students were all so sweet and eager to get to know me, and I was surprised that they addressed me as ‘Miss Kristen’ without even being told.  At the beginning of each day the teacher, Ms. Ramos, would provide me with her lesson plan for that morning.  The typical day consisted of English spelling, grammar, and reading.  I would assist kids that were struggling, read to them, and answer any question that they had to the best of my ability.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dear Reader</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/introduction/2017/03/30/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dear Reader" /><published>2017-03-30T12:14:01-04:00</published><updated>2017-03-30T12:14:01-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/introduction/2017/03/30/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/FOVM.github.io/introduction/2017/03/30/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Forum Web Archive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forum is a magazine written, produced, and published by the students
of Villanova University. The views expressed in Forum do not necessarily
represent the views of Villanova University. Each article, column,
piece or any other written statement is a representation of the author’s
opinion, or, but not necessarily including, Forum staff in general. As
always, we welcome your feedback, responses, and of course, lively
conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Forum apertus est.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Forum Editors</name></author><category term="Introduction" /><summary type="html">Welcome to the Forum Web Archive.</summary></entry></feed>